<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>HPRP and Household Consumption</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/09/22/HPRP/"/>
    <url>2019/09/22/HPRP/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="https://polyfill.io/v3/polyfill.min.js?features=es6"></script><script id="MathJax-script" async src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/mathjax@3/es5/tex-mml-chtml.js"></script><div style="text-align: justify">This is an on-going research of mine. I am still on the search for instrumental variables. I believe it could be an interesting thesis for my PhD studies.</div><h3 id="1-Introduction"><a href="#1-Introduction" class="headerlink" title="1 Introduction"></a>1 Introduction</h3><div style="text-align: justify">The mid 1990s witnessed a drastic and long-lasting boom in China’s real estate sector.  The hike in housing prices was primarily realized through the following two channels: first, incentivized by enormous fiscal revenue from selling lands to real estate developers, local governments forcefully introduced a series of policies that accelerate the development of housing markets; second, after abandoning the welfare housing system, city residents’ demands on housing hikes. Plus, with the advancements in marketization, the wealth effect of lands and housing also makes them considerably appealing to investors. As a result, housing prices have been skyrocketing: real growth in house prices averages 10% per annum since 2006 (Gyourko et al, 2016).<br><br>While the real estate sector remains a key component of the Chinese economy, the soaring housing prices engender concerns related to the stability of China’s financial system and macro fundamentals, as well as to the welfare of individual household. The authorities have certainly recognized these issues. Since 2005, a series of policies were enacted to regulate the housing market. First introduced in 2010, Housing Purchase Restriction Policy (HPRP) remains one of the most powerful policy tools to curb the soaring housing prices. According to the “NO. 10 National Notice” (2010) issued by the State Council, non-residents (people without registered permanent residency, or “Hukou” ) who paid taxes or social security for less than a year to the city they reside would not be eligible for mortgage loans. It also granted municipalities the authority to control the number of houses or apartments residents and nonresidents can buy. Temporarily relaxed in 2014, HPRP now remains in action in 60 cities.<br><br>There have been plenty of measures and studies on the regulation the housing markets, but most of them target at the supply side. Gyourko and Molloy (2015) has done an impressive work reviewing research on housing supply regulations (outside China), and concluded that based on available evidence, most studies found negative net welfare effects from regulations. Measures that restrict housing demands, however, are rare. In this sense, HPRP is valuable as it serves as a unique social experiment complementing the studies on market regulations. Just like other types of government interventions, HPRP has great implications on social welfare. There exists abundant literature on HPRP and its effects. Most, if not all, focus on its interactions with housing markets. A bulk of research examine the interdependency between HPRP and housing prices (Zhang, 2016). Some research focuses on how HPRP influences housing markets and how these impacts may differ (Du, 2015; Fang, 2018; Cao and Huang, 2015; Cao, 2017; Lu, 2018; Tzur-Ilan, 2016; Fang, 2018; Chen, 2018; Wu, 2016; Wu and Li, 2017). There do exist some attempts evaluating the welfare effects of HPRP, but mostly by building theoretical frameworks (Li, 2011; Hu 2011; Feng and He, 2012). In addition, it is also useful to evaluate the variations in welfare consequences across different groups (Gyourko, 2015). Thus, I am interested in how HPRP reshape the welfare of individual households, especially how the effects might differ across families with distinct characteristics.<br><br>In this study, I intend to measure the net effects of HPRP on household consumption which is a commonly used proxy for welfare (Garner et al, 2003). HPRP is meant to increase the affordability of housings by stifling speculative demands. When housing purchases are restricted, money that is originally spent on housing will then be diverted into either the consumption of other goods or reinvestments on other assets (Mao, 2011). On the other hand, housing also serves as a capital good whose value grows with price. As evaluated by Wu et al (2012), the expected capital gain from housing is quite high in China. As a result, under HPRP, families can no longer invest in the housing market and thus lose one avenue for investing. Decreases in future returns might discourage household consumption. In addition, whether families regard housings as necessities or means of investments should be primarily determined by household characteristics such as financial conditions and preferences. Thus, depending on individual characteristics, influences of HPRP on households vary. There exist several channels via which HPRP introduced differential impacts (Feng and He, 2012). Families owning one or more houses can be driven away from housing to other consumption markets by HPRP. Alternatively, families that have not owned housings and are not eligible for purchase might increase savings. As these forces are in opposite directions, I am curious about the net effects of HPRP on households’ consumption and how these effects vary across groups. Whilst research on the dynamics of housings prices and consumption is plentiful, few are conducted in the context of HPRP (Dong et al, 2017). Moreover, existing researches at best touched on the effects of HPRP from a macro perspective (Zhang, 2016; Du et al, 2015; Lu, 2018). Few analyzes HPRP from a micro level (Mo, 2015). Although there have already been some works on the correlations between HPRP and consumption, they either focus solely on housing markets or use macro-level data (Mo, 2015; Feng and He, 2012). With access to micro-level data on household finance and demographic features, this paper will try to find empirical evidence on how HPRP influences the welfare of individual family.<br><br>Given the dramatic variations in specific terms of HPRP adopted by municipalities, our study focuses on one specific regulation used by nearly all cities – the number of houses a family can purchase given their “Hukou” and housing ownership status, and control for other bundled policies. I also care most about how HPRP influences households’ consumption on goods other than housing, particularly on education and entertainment. Inverse demand system will be used given the fact that HPRP is constraining the quantity of demand, which makes it more appropriate to take quantity as exogenous when analyzing the markets. To compare how the effects of HPRP might differ regarding individual attributes, I will first identify households living in cities that have enforced HPRP, then utilize Propensity Score Matching (PSM) to construct a control group from households (in other regions) not subject to HPRP but with similar characteristics. Several features characterize HPRP as a quasi-experiment: first, cities have some latitude in determining whether to adopt HPRP or not; second, some cities implemented HPRP while others did not; third, eligibility under HPRP can be argued to be exogenous – “Hukou” and number of houses owned were generally determined prior to the HPRP. In order to measure and compare how the results might differ across different types of households, I divide households into three groups based on the attributes of their demands. We are then able to measure the causal relations between HPRP and the consumption of different types of households via a Difference-in-Difference approach (DiD).</div><h3 id="2-Theoretical-framework-and-hypothesis"><a href="#2-Theoretical-framework-and-hypothesis" class="headerlink" title="2 Theoretical framework and hypothesis"></a>2 Theoretical framework and hypothesis</h3><h4 id="2-1-The-loss-of-welfare-induced-by-HPRP"><a href="#2-1-The-loss-of-welfare-induced-by-HPRP" class="headerlink" title="2.1 The loss of welfare induced by HPRP"></a>2.1 The loss of welfare induced by HPRP</h4><div style="text-align: justify">In light of the studies on Harberger Triangle of welfare and the supply and demand model (Glaeser 2003; Hu, 2011; Feng and He, 2012; Canning and Vroomen, 2019), HPRP and its interaction with the housing market can be presented as the following graph.</div><p><img src="/img/g1.png" alt="graph 1"></p><div style="text-align: justify">HPRP restricts housing purchase by a set of regulatory criteria, including “Hukou”, the number of housings owned by households and the amount of down payment. This design is equivalent to dividing up consumer population into groups based on their eligibility. New demands in housing markets are subsamples from each group (Hu, 2011). Thus, the demand curve would shift inward under HPRP (\(D’\) in Graph 1). Notice that for individual households in the same group, their eligibility of housing purchase is the same. I then assume that the “sampling process” within each group is somewhat random. Further notice that I cannot determine the allocation among different groups and its correlations with group characteristics without empirical evidence. That is, I do not make any specific assumptions about the intercept and the slope of \(D’\). In Graph 1, I let \(D’\) have a smaller elasticity compared to \(D\), but it can be just the opposite in reality.<br><br>Technically, HPRP is very likely to induce welfare loss. The welfare loss generated by HPRP is then determined by the slope and intercept of this new curve (Graph 1). Note that \(D’\) represents the new demand curve under HPRP. The deadweight loss (DWL) from HPRP is the polygon BOCF. This DWL is assumed to be greater than a quantity control scenario (denoted by the vertical line AC) by the area of BACF.</div><h4 id="2-2-Inverse-demand-system-of-housing-and-other-goods"><a href="#2-2-Inverse-demand-system-of-housing-and-other-goods" class="headerlink" title="2.2 Inverse demand system of housing and other goods"></a>2.2 Inverse demand system of housing and other goods</h4><div style="text-align: justify">The main idea of this paper is to evaluate the effects of HPRP on household consumption. Specifically, I am interested in what category of consumption will be impacted by HPRP. There are four “outcome” variables of interest: household expenses on education, household expenses on entertainment, household expenses on housing , and total household expenses. Theoretically, HPRP distorts the equilibrium of housing market, shifting the market demand as it puts a cap on the quantity of houses consumers can purchase. With predetermined budget constraints, households will then alter expenses on other goods. It is worth noting that since HPRP targets on the quantity of demand rather than the market prices, individual household takes the quantity (\(Q\)) as given with prices as a function of quantity (\(P(Q)\)). Therefore, I propose to apply inverse demand system in this paper. The inverse demand in housing market can be expressed as:</div><div style="text-align: center"> \(P_D^h=a_D^h-b_D^h Q_D^h+r_D^h X_D^h+ϵ_D^h\) (1)</div><div style="text-align: justify">Where \(P_D^h\) is housing price, \(Q_D^h\) is the quantity, and \(X_D^h\) is a vector of factors that correlated to market prices (i.e. market shifters). In parallel, the inverse supply is:</div><div style="text-align: center"> \(P_S^h=a_S^h+b_S^h Q_S^h+r_S^h X_S^h+ϵ_S^h\) (2)</div><div style="text-align: justify">The equilibrium in housing market can then be calculated by solving for \(P_D = P_S\), which is:</div><div style="text-align: center"> \(Q_h=(a_D^h-a_S^h+r_D^h X_D^h-r_S^h X_S^h+ϵ_D^h-ϵ_S^h)/(b_D^h+b_S^h )\) (3)\(P_h=(b_S^h a_D^h+b_D^h a_S^h+b_S^h r_D^h X_D^h+b_D^h r_S^h X_S^h+b_D^h ϵ_S^h+b_S^h ϵ_D^h)/(b_D^h+b_S^h )\) (4)</div><div style="text-align: justify">Since we assume that demand of education  is under the influence of housing market distortion, the market demand and supply in education market will then be:</div><div style="text-align: center">\(P_D^e=a_D^e-b_D^e Q_D^e-b_D^h Q_D^h+r_D^e X_D^e+ϵ_D^e\) (5)</div><div style="text-align: center">\(P_S^e=a_S^e+b_S^e Q_S^e+r_S^e X_S^e+ϵ_S^e\) (6)</div>Solving for the education market equilibrium gives us the following function:<div style="text-align: center">\(Q_e=A+B_1 X_D^h+B_2 X_S^h+B_3 X_D^e+B_4 X_S^e+ϵ\) (7)</div><div style="text-align: center">\(P_e=Ζ+γ_1 X_D^h+γ_2 X_S^h+γ_3 X_D^e+γ_4 X_S^e+ϵ\) (8)</div><div style="text-align: justify">where \(Q_e\) is the demand of education (or other goods); \(P_e\) is the price of education; \(X_D^h\) is a vector of factors that influence demand of housing; \(X_S^h\) is a vector of factors that influence supply of housing; \(X_D^e\) is a vector of factors that influence demand of education (or other goods); and \(X_S^e\) is a vector of factors that influence supply of education (or other goods). Coefficients \(A, B, Z\) and \(γ\) can be expressed as functions of \(a_D^e,b_D^e,b_D^h,r_D^e\) and etc. Since \(P_e\) and \(Q_e\) are endogenous and correlated to housing market shifters \(X_D^h\) and \(X_S^h\), HPRP and its effects are also endogenous in education markets. Thus, it is not possible to evaluate the causal effects of HPRP on education (or other goods) market with simple linear model.<br><br>Another challenge we are confronting is the selection bias problem. This is resulted from the nature of HPRP: though it was initiated by the central government of P. R. China, municipalities still enjoyed discretions of whether and when to implement it. As a result, cities chose to adopt HPRP (adopter) can be fundamentally different from cities chose not to (non-adopter). For example, adopters are usually more developed and have higher housing prices than non-adopters. Families living in these two types of cities are also different from each other. Such differences can be correlated to their decisions on consumption and thus bias our estimations.<br><br>To address these two issues, I propose to use Propensity Score Matching (PSM) and Difference-in-Difference (DID) methods. PSM allows me to construct comparable “treatment” and “control” group based on household-level attributes, which addresses the selection bias issue and lay the ground for DID analysis. DID can then cross out the endogenous factors influencing the market demand as long as these factors have similar trend. For the PSM-DID estimation to be valid, several assumptions should be met:</div><ul><li>The trend of the treatment and control group is parallel.</li><li>The allocation of HPRP does not depend on outcomes of interest.</li><li>No spillover effects of HPRP on control group.</li></ul><div style="text-align: justify">Available data only cover one year before HPRP and two years after. Thus, I argue that the “parallel trend” assumption would hold in such a short timeframe. Moreover, since the outcome variables are essentially the consumption on education and entertainment, and since the municipalities chose to adopt HPRP primarily based on market indicators such as housing prices and cities’ administrative level (capitals of provinces are the first to implement HPRP), it is safe to assume that the allocation of HPRP is not based on household consumption. I further assume that HPRP imposes a parallel shift  to the education demand curve (namely, the intercept \(a_D^e\) is now \(a_D^e+μ\)). Therefore, the education demand of the control and treatment group before and after HPRP would be:</div><div style="text-align: center">\(Q_{D,t_0}^C=A_{t_0}+B_1 X_{D,t_0}^h+B_2 X_{S,t_0}^h+B_3 X_{D,t_0}^e+B_4 X_{S,t_0}^e+ϵ_{t_0}\) (9)</div><div style="text-align: center">\(Q_{D,t_0}^T=C_{t_0}+B_1 X_{D,t_0}^h+B_2 X_{S,t_0}^h+B_3 X_{D,t_0}^e+B_4 X_{S,t_0}^e+ϵ_{t_0}\) (10)</div><div style="text-align: center">\(Q_{D,t_1}^C=A_{t_1}+B_1 X_{D,t_1}^h+B_2 X_{S,t_1}^h+B_3 X_{D,t_1}^e+B_4 X_{S,t_1}^e+ϵ_{t_1}\) (11)</div><div style="text-align: center">\(Q_{D,t_1}^T=C_{t_1}+B_1 X_{D,t_1}^h+B_2 X_{S,t_1}^h+B_3 X_{D,t_1}^e+B_4 X_{S,t_1}^e+ϵ_{t_1}\) (12)</div><div style="text-align: justify">Under the assumptions above, we have \(A_{t_0 }=A_{t_1 }=A(b_D^h,b_D^e,b_S^h,b_S^e)\), while \(C_{t_0 }=C(b_D^h,b_D^e,b_S^h,b_S^e)\) and \(C_{t_1}=C(b_D^h,b_D^e,b_S^h,b_S^e,μ)\). I am also assuming that the changes in \(X_D^h,X_S^h,X_D^e,X_S^e\) (observables) and \(ϵ_{t_1}\) (unobservables) across time are the same between the treatment and control group, so they will get crossed out when we do DID analysis. By adding \(X_D^h,X_S^h,X_D^e,X_S^e\) in the DID regression, we can soften the parallel assumption on the observables. However, the unobservables might still bias the estimations if they do not have parallel trend. Thus, it is critical to include the “correct” controls and to interpret the unobservables as having similar trend. As a result, the DID estimator is essentially:</div><div style="text-align: center">\(DID=(Q_{D,t_1}^T-Q_{D,t_0}^T )-(Q_{D,t_1}^C-Q_{D,t_0}^C)=C_{t_1 }-C_{t_0 }=C(b_D^h,b_D^e,b_S^h,b_S^e,μ)\) (13)</div><div style="text-align: justify">This measure partly serves my intention of doing causal inference on HPRP and household consumption. However, what we are really interested in should be the size of \(μ\). A possible solution is to use instrumental variables for HPRP. I am currently on the search for instruments, and the following two occur to me as plausible options: the supply of land and geographical measures such as terrains or elevations.</div><h3 id="3-Descriptive-Statistics-and-PSM"><a href="#3-Descriptive-Statistics-and-PSM" class="headerlink" title="3 Descriptive Statistics and PSM"></a>3 Descriptive Statistics and PSM</h3><div style="text-align: justify">The data I use for this research come from two sources: the first one is China Family Panel Studies (CFPS) offered by Peking University and the second one is a city-level dataset collected by me and a small group of students from Renmin University of China. CFPS is a survey carried out every two years. Thus, it is important to determine whether the data was collected before or after the introduction of HPRP. As shown in the following timetable (Table 1), it is safe to interpret data of 2010 as “before” the implementation of HPRP and 2012 – 2014 as “after”.  Then two steps are taken to perform PSM:Step 1: probit model is used to estimate the probability (or the “propensity score”) of each household to be “adopters” of HPRP.<div style="text-align: center">\(p_i=Prob[HPRP=1|X]\) (14)</div>Here \(p_i\) is the probability/propensity of family \(i\), and \(X\) denotes a vector of controls representing family attributes.Step 2: I then use Kernel-based Matching (KBM) method to match each family in treatment group to several families (with different weights) in control groups. The radius of matching is 0.025.</div><p><img src="/img/table1.png" alt="table1"></p><div style="text-align: justify">With matched treatment and control groups, I then perform DID analysis and estimate the average treatment effects on the treated (ATT). Besides this PSM-DID approach, I also use the fixed effect model to estimate the impacts of HPRP as a robustness check.<br><br>For PSM-DID model, I drop observations from Beijing to ensure that we have a neat sample containing information from both “before” and “after” HPRP. This gives me a sample size of 8921 from 124 cities, half of which have adopted HPRP. Families are matched using data of 2010 so that the effects of HPRP would not distort the matching. The treatment is HPRP, and families ever living in cities adopting HPRP are allocated in the treatment group. Other families are then automatically grouped in the control group. Prior to matching, t-test is run to determined if the treatment and control group have significantly different attributes (including hukou status, household head age, family size and number of housing owned by the family etc.). Results are presented in Table 2. In short, families in the treatment and control group are different, so without any adjustment, a direct estimation using these data will be subject to selection bias.</div><p><img src="/img/table2.png" alt="table2"></p><div style="text-align: justify">I then perform PSM based on the family level controls. KBM is used to match families in treatment group with families in control group. With KBM, every “untreated” observation will be assigned different weights and used to construct the control group, which allow for the inclusion of more information in later regression. Table 3 presents the balance test results after matching. All attributes are balanced, so the matching is successful.</div><p><img src="/img/table3.png" alt="table3"></p><h3 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference"></a>Reference</h3><div style="text-align: justify">Breslaw, J. and Smith, B. J., “Measuring Welfare Changes When Quantity is Constrained”, Journal of Business & Economic Statistics, 13(1): 95 – 103, 1995.<p>Caliendo, M., and Kopeinig, S., “Some Practical Guidance for the Implementation of Propensity Score Matching.” Social Science Electronic Publishing 22.1 31-72, 2010.</p><p>Cao J., Huang B., and Lai R. N., “On the Effectiveness of Housing Purchase Restriction Policy in China: A Difference in Difference Approach[J]”, Social Science Electronic Publishing, 2017.</p><p>Chen, J., Man, H. E. C., Seiler, M. J., &amp; Zhang, H., “Household tenure choice and housing price volatility under a binding home-purchase limit policy constraint”, Journal of Housing Economics, S1051137718300615-, 2018.</p><p>Dong, Z., E. C. M. Hui., and S. H. Jia. “How does housing price affect consumption in China: Wealth effect or substitution effect?” Cities 64(2017):1-8.</p><p>Du Z, Zhang L., “Home-purchase restriction, property tax and housing price in China: A counterfactual analysis[J]”. Journal of Econometrics, 188(2): S0304407615000871, 2015.</p><p>Garner, T. I., and R. C. Sastre. “The Influence of Demographics and Household-Specific Price Indices on Consumption-Based Inequality and Welfare: A Comparison of Spain and the United States.” Southern Economic Journal 70.1(2003):22-48.</p><p>Glaeser, E. L., and Luttmer, E. F., “The Misallocation of Housing under Rent Control”, American Economic Review, 93(4), 1027-1046, 2003.</p><p>Gyourko, J., “Regulation and Housing Supply”, Handbook of Regional and Urban Economics, edited by (Gilles Duranton, J. Vernon Henderson and William Strange). Vol. 5A, Elsevier, Amsterdam, The Netherlands: Chapter 19: 1289-1338, 2015.</p><p>Gyourko, J., Wu, J., Deng, Y., “Evaluating the Risk of Chinese Housing Markets: What We Know and What We Need to Know”, China Economic Review, 39: 91-144, 2016.<br>Heckman, J., et al. “Characterizing Selection Bias Using Experimental Data.”<br>Econometrica 66.5(1998):1017.</p><p>Howard, D. H., “Rationing, Quantity Constraints, and Consumption Theory”, Econometrica, 45, 399-412, 1977.</p><p>Kassie, Menale, B. Shiferaw , and G. Muricho . “Agricultural Technology, Crop Income, and Poverty Alleviation in Uganda.” World Development 39.10(2011):1784-1795.</p><p>Kim, Y. H., “Inverse demand system and welfare measurement in quantity space”, Working Paper, Western Kentucky University, Bowling Green, Kentucky, 1997.</p><p>Mendola, Mariapia. “Agricultural technology adoption and poverty reduction: A propensity-score matching analysis for rural Bangladesh.” Food Policy 32.3(2007):372-393.</p><p>Rosenbaum, Paul R., and D. B. Rubin. “Constructing a Control Group Using Multivariate Matched Sampling Methods That Incorporate the Propensity Score.” The American Statistician39.1(1985):33-38.</p><p>Smith, Jeffrey A., and P. E. Todd. “Does matching overcome LaLonde’s critique of nonexperimental estimators?” Journal of Econometrics 125.1-2(2005):305-353.</p><p>Tzur-Ilan N., “Unintended Consequences of Credit Constraints on Housing: The Case of LTV Limits[J]”, Social Science Electronic Publishing, 2016.</p><p>Wu, J., Gyourko, J., Deng, Y., “Evaluating Conditions in Major Chinese Housing Markets”, Regional Science and Urban Economics, 42: 531-543, 2012.</p><p>曹清峰, “空间‘邻近效应’与地方政府住房限购政策的实施”, 南开经济研究, (01):77-89, 2017.</p><p>陈明星,陆大道,张华, “中国城市化水平的综合测度及其动力因子分析”, 地理学报, 64(4): 387-398, 2009.</p><p>陈飞,翟伟娟, “农户行为视角下农地流转诱因及其福利效应研究”, 经济研究, (10): 163-177, 2015.</p><p>方兴, “中国房地产限购政策能够有效抑制房价上涨吗——基于70个大中城市的实证研究”,财经科学, (01): 41-53, 2018.</p><p>冯科, 何理. “中国房地产市场“限购政策”研究——基于反需求函数的理论与经验分析.” 经济学动态 2(2012):53-60. (Feng Ke, He Li. “Research on the “Restriction Purchase Policy” of China’s Real Estate Market——Based on the Theory and Empirical Analysis of Anti-demand Function.”)</p><p>胡涛, 孙振尧, “限购政策与社会福利:一个理论探讨”, 经济科学, (06): 42-49, 2011. (Hu Tao, Sun Zhenduo, “Restriction Policy and Social Welfare: A Theoretical Discussion”, Economic Science)</p><p>李祎恒, “住房分配机制中限购令政策的法经济学解析” 法学论坛, (03): 106-111, 2011.</p><p>卢阳, 李若溦, “限购令对房地产价格影响的实证分析——基于全国32个大中城市数据”, 金融经济, (08): 26-28, 2018.</p><p>莫家颖, 弋代春. “限购政策对中国住房消费性与投资性需求的影响研究.” 投资研究 10(2015):110-123.</p><p>吴雪婷, “限购政策对住房市场价格与租金的影响研究[D]”, 华东师范大学, 2016.</p><p>吴耀国, 杜江, 邓国营. “限购政策对住房市场影响的实证分析  .” 统计与决策 22(2016): 126-129,共4页.</p><p>张索迪, “限购政策对住房市场的价—量影响效应及城市间差异性研究[D]”, 清华大学, 2016.</p></div><p></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>research</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Videos on Inverse Demand System</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/08/11/ids/"/>
    <url>2019/08/11/ids/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inverse demand system is the inverse function of the traditional demand system. It is rather valuable for empirical research (Hicks, 1956; Baker and Bresnahan, 1988; Barten and Bettendorf, 1989; Kim, 1997). However, there lacks straight-forward illustration of inverse demand system. Thus, I made these videos primarily based on the work of Kim (1997), talking about the duality of inverse demand function and the normal demand function, as well as the welfare measures (namely compensating and equivalent variation) in the inverse demand system. I also elaborate a bit on the empirical application of these two demand functions.</p><p>Note: I apply this model in my paper on House-Purchase Restriction Policy.</p><p><strong>Please follow the links below to watch the videos.</strong></p><ol><li>Inverse Demand System: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=quP6k0Tf9n8&t=414s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the basic idea and a simple example</a>;</li><li>Inverse Demand System: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3lziGScipZ0&t=6s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">welfare measures (CV &amp; EV)</a>;</li><li>Inverse Demand System: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Bx6ntuny-g&t=6s" target="_blank" rel="noopener">empirical application (a general discussion)</a>.</li></ol><p>I referred to the following 2 paper to make the videos:<br>Kim, H.Y. 1997. Inverse Demand Systems and Welfare Measurement in Quantity Space. Western Kentucky University. Bowling Green, Kentucky.<br>冯科. 何理. 2012. 中国房地产市场限购政策研究————基于反需求函数的理论与经验分析. 经济学动态, (2), pp 53-60. (in Chinese)</p><p>Other reference:<br>Hicks, J.R. 1956. Revision of Demand Theory. Oxford: Clarendon Press.<br>Baker, J.B., Bresnahan, T.F. 1988. Estimating the Residual Demand Curve Facing a Single Firm. International Journal of Industrial Organization, pp 283-300.<br>Barten, A.P., Bettendorf, L.J. 1989. Price Formation of Fish: an Application of an Inverse Demand System. European Economic Review, pp 1509-1525.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>presentation</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Inequality of Opportunity in China</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/07/15/io/"/>
    <url>2019/07/15/io/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is an independent research paper. I have submitted it to China Economic Review.</em></p><p>There are rich literature studying the effects of inequality. However, empirical research often reach inconsistent conclusions. Following the work of Roemer (1992), I argue that inequality can be decomposed, and its components have diverging impacts. The concept of inequality of opportunity (IO) as an alternative measure of inequality is proposed by both economists and sociologists (Winslow, 1952; Dworkin, 1981; Sen, 1985). Formerly defined by Roemer (1993), IO stands for inequality induced by factors (or circumstances) beyond the control of individuals, including gender, race, parents’ attributions, etc., while another source of inequality (inequality of effort, or IE) emerge from differences in individual efforts or subjective choices such as occupations and investments in education. Blume and Durlauf (2001) buttressed this idea in their book, arguing that the persistence of inequality is attributable to the circumstances. Other scholars empirically applied IO to evaluate its effects on diverse socioeconomic topics like economic growth (Marrero and Rodriguez, 2013; Bradbury and Triest, 2016), investments in human capital (Mejia and St-Pierre, 2008; Song and Zhou, 2019) and emergence of child labor (Emerson and Knabb, 2005). In short, IO levies negative impacts on the wellbeing of society.</p><p>In this paper, I intend to empirically test the effects of IO on social stability in China. With access to national census data of 2005, I construct a measure of IO on county level. I then merge the county-level data of publicized mass incidents to census data and test the correlations between IO and both the occurrence and frequency of mass incidents. It proves that IO does positively correlated with the happening of mass incidents. Namely, in counties with greater IO, there are both a higher probability and more records of mass incidents. The results hold in both robustness tests I perform subsequently – one is to employ another measure of IO, the other is to aggregate the data to provincial level. I also examine mechanism through which IO could impact the stability of society. In particular, hukou seems to play a momentous role in passing on the effects of IO to social stability. Regions with higher ratio of floating population (defined as residents without local hukou) suffer from more incidents of social unrests. It can be inferred from this finding that people might care more about the egalitarian distributions of social rights such as accessing resources of education and social security. This is because hukou is often used as a threshold determining who get the priority in the distributions of (some) public goods.</p><p>My work contributes to the existing body of literature in the following ways. Frist of all, to the best of my knowledge, though a bulk of analysis can be found on inequality and/or IO and the socioeconomic effects, there still lacks research directly examine the relationship between IO and mass incidents. This paper, as a result, serves to fill this gap of knowledge. Second, this is amongst the first attempts to use county-level data of China to study IO. It is also one of the first studies on the effects of IO on social stability with social unrests data of China. In comparison to research whose scope expands beyond counties, my paper avoids potential biases introduced by the distinctions in history, culture and political institutions among countries. I also examine the heterogeneous nature of IO across region by grouping counties based on economic features such as GDP per capita, fiscal expenditure and shares of three sectors. Results indicate that IO in general has greater effects on more underdeveloped areas. Third, this paper is one of the first attempts exploring mechanisms via which IO rather than inequality sways social stability. I assess channels through which IO could alter the happening of mass incidents, and determine one possible explanation for the positive correlation: in counties with higher level of IO, there is also a larger size of floating population. Moreover, counties with higher share of floating population suffer from substantially greater probabilities and frequencies of mass incidents.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>research</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>JFK &amp; Reagan Revolution</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/03/09/jfk-revolution/"/>
    <url>2019/03/09/jfk-revolution/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of <strong><em>JFK and the Reagan Revolution: A Secret History of American Prosperity</em></strong> by <strong>Lawrence Kudlow</strong>.</p><p>It was a gift from the bully pulpit for China’s trade representatives, and I was asked to translate two chapters of it into Chinese.</p><p>看这两章，我了解到了treasury和CEA和总统的互动。而且还让我联想到之前看到的一篇文章，讲为什么现在美国总统的权力越来越大了。其实从经济政策来看，1950年代权力就已经有些超出宪法规定的边界了吧？</p><p>肯尼迪从艾森豪威尔手里接过一个经济衰退的美国，他组建的经济顾问团队对经济政策有截然不同的想法。一边认为要全面减税；另一边则觉得应该大幅增加财政支出、兴办公共工程。kudlow说肯尼迪是那种会一个一个方法试过去的人，不知道这里面有没有黑的成分。但从他后来的选择来看确实是这样，他做决定的首要动机是维持金本位制度、固定汇率（面子问题？），然后才是发现经济仍然死气沉沉、竞选承诺要实现不了了，再推出后面的政策。</p><p>果然任何事情归根结底都是关于政治的。”Of the people, by the bureaucrats, for the bureaucrats.”</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>book review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Trumponomics</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/01/29/trumponomics/"/>
    <url>2019/01/29/trumponomics/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of <strong><em>Trumponomics</em></strong> by <strong>Stephen Moore &amp; Arthur B. Laffer</strong>.</p><p>这本书是2018年出的，特朗普竞选团队的经济学家试图向大家系统地解释一系列政策背后的逻辑。写法上相当随意，很多时候想到哪写到哪，政治色彩非常强，所以自始自终不太能说服我。</p><p>在这本书里特朗普被描绘成了一个遗世独立的政治天才，有绝佳的经济和政治直觉，在promoting这件事上极具天赋。而与之相对的奥巴马和希拉里则更像是趾高气昂、不顾普通民众死活的政治精英，一意孤行地推着一堆注定失败的政策。</p><p>撇去内容不谈（逻辑陷阱太多了，估计这本书最大的目的也不是要让大家相信特朗普那一套真的完美无缺），这本书给我最大的感触是，我们确实迎来了一个变革与转向的时代：“政治正确”的含义改变了，特朗普反绿色运动、反全球化、反自由贸易，拥护民粹、国家主义，基本是一个彻头彻尾“政治不正确”的人。但就算书里所有的经济学狡辩都是错的，它至少说对了一件事，那就是他赢了，确确实实地获得了大部分美国人的支持。</p><p>这种支持很好理解，现在美国大部分人，包括商人、政客、学者，都是冷战时期成长起来的。但对于我们来说，这种对特朗普的支持最大的问题就是中国的国际形象和地位在他们看来不是正面的，而我们自身的实力还负担不起这种带有敌意的眼光。</p><p>联想到民粹掌权的意大利、默克尔下台后的德国、还有一团乱麻的英国，我只觉得世界的风向正在转弯，但没有人知道下一个阶段新的righteousness会是什么，大概特朗普们自己都不知道。</p><p>题外话：这本书推荐给喜欢追星并给偶像写小论文的人，看了你就知道，原来崇拜和溜须拍马还可以这么高级。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>book review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Good Food Purchasing Program in LA</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/12/09/gfpp/"/>
    <url>2017/12/09/gfpp/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a class project for the course, Introduction to Programming for Public Policy.</em></p><p>Good Food Purchasing Program (GFPP) is an initiative first implemented by Los Angeles in 2012. Public schools are the main bodies adopting this policy. The main idea is to procure meals from local food business and apply harsher standards of nutrition, raw material sources and environmental influences. GFPP has five value criteria: animal welfare, nutrition, support for local business, rights of employees (such as safety and justice), and environmental sustainability. This project aims to identify the effects of this program on local socioeconomic development. As GFPP has been marked as a priority in several other cities, including Austin, Chicago, Cincinnati, Oakland and Twin Cities, and there lack quantitative evaluation of the program, our project can serve as a reference for these other cities in the potential outcomes of GFPP.</p><p>Specifically, we employed data on public schools from California Department of Education. We treat public schools in LA county as “the treated”, and use the others as the control group. Then using Difference-in-Difference analysis, we attempt to find the causal relations between the implementation of GFPP and the health outcomes of public school students. Based on the regression results, we conclude that It has not been demonstrated obvious benefits on students’ physical fitness resulting from the GFPP yet. However, it does not necessarily mean that GFPP does not have any impacts on students’ health. As a matter of fact, nutrition-related policies usually have more significant influences on the health outcomes of younger children and children from poorer families. In fact, given that Los Angeles is well-developed and has been implementing GFPP only for 4 years, our results are not especially surprising. Unfortunately, due to the limited data and time we have, we fail to conduct more rigorous quantitative analysis and refine our project.</p><p><strong>Please refer to this <a href="https://lizhong-liu.github.io/GFPP_DiD/">link</a> for the website for the project, and this <a href="https://github.com/Lizhong-Liu/GFPP_DiD" target="_blank" rel="noopener">link</a> to the Github site.</strong></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>research</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Courage to Act</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/09/28/courage/"/>
    <url>2017/09/28/courage/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of <strong><em>The Courage to Act: A Memoir of A Crisis and Its Aftermath</em></strong> by <strong>Ben Bernanke</strong>.</p><ol><li><p>This book solves a lot of puzzles on central banking for me. The first one coming into my mind should be the “boundary issue”. On the one hand, central banks should maintain its nonpartisan stance so that it can “moves” the market objectively. On the other hand, it is also the responsibility of central bankers to coordinate the economic policies and make sure everything is in alignment of the policy targets. In addition, should we expect the central banks to foresee systematic risks and acts as a safety net when crises hit the economy?</p></li><li><p>It seems that the priority of monetary policy making is to consider what the change in policy could do to the market expectation. Quote Mr. Bernanke, 98% of the effectiveness of monetary policy depends on communication with the market. However, examples offered in the book (such as the implementation of quantitative easing and the rescue of )</p></li><li><p>I was always wondering if it is rational to use “cycle” to explain the booms and busts of literally every macroeconomic phenomenon, and use this line of logic to forecast the future. Does history really repeat itself? Mr. Bernanke did mention this question in his book, though he simply quoted Mark Twain that “history may rhyme, but does not repeat itself”. So now the question becomes: to what extent would history rhyme?</p></li><li><p>The fuses of crises often seem to be bank runs (though in different forms). So what is the root of crises? What makes the market panic at the very beginning? Is there a factor that can conclude these panics?</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>book review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>From Trash to Treasure</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/08/09/trash/"/>
    <url>2017/08/09/trash/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>In college, I initiated a research on waste sorting in 5 cities in China. I evaluated the waste sorting policies and their implementation in these cities. In 2017, invited by Dr. Jennifer Turner from Wilson Center, I extended the scope of the research and concentrated on the handling of food waste in China. I then composed this blogpost for the Environmental Change and Security Program of Wilson Center.</em></p><p><strong>Please follow this <a href="https://www.newsecuritybeat.org/2017/08/trash-treasure-effective-sorting-helps-china-utilize-food-waste/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">link</a> for the original post.</strong></p><p>Launched in Beijing in 2013, the highly successful grassroots <a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-21711928" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“Empty Your Plate”</a> campaign encourages Chinese consumers to eliminate food waste from their meals. Starting with <a href="http://focus.weibo.com/pub/i/zt/weibozhanshi" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog posts</a> on Weibo (China’s equivalent of Twitter), this campaign rapidly swept the entire country and attracted support from <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/28/world/asia/xi-jinping-imposes-austerity-measures-on-chinas-elite.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the</a> central government, which later issued <a href="https://www.chinainternetwatch.com/9769/forbid-catering-operators-to-set-minimum-consumption/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a series of policies</a> urging restaurants to use smaller dishes and remove minimum charges. However, the volume of food waste in China is still astonishing.</p><p>From 2013 to 2015, China generated <a href="http://www.china.org.cn/china/2016-12/09/content_39882640.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">17-18 million</a> tons of food waste each year—enough to feed 30-50 million people. This not only wastes natural resources including fresh water, arable land, and energy, but also severely impacts the urban environment. When improperly disposed, food waste can pollute water, degrade the soil, and increase emissions of greenhouse gases. But with effective sorting and repurposing, food waste can become a valuable resource that can be used to produce biofuels, chemicals, animal feed, and compost.</p><h3 id="Sorting-A-Gateway-to-Reutilizing-Food-Waste"><a href="#Sorting-A-Gateway-to-Reutilizing-Food-Waste" class="headerlink" title="Sorting: A Gateway to Reutilizing Food Waste"></a>Sorting: A Gateway to Reutilizing Food Waste</h3><p>Like many other countries in the world, reusing food waste is not yet common practice in China. When kitchens and restaurants throw away their scraps, food waste is mixed with other city garbage, compressed at processing facilities, and then transported to landfills or incinerators via transfer stations. Food scraps usually comprise <a href="http://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/agriculture-and-food/food-losses-and-food-waste-in-china_5jz5sq5173lq-en;jsessionid=4pcrr65cmof5l.x-oecd-live-02" target="_blank" rel="noopener">50 to 70 percent</a> of China’s municipal solid waste, a much higher percentage than that of the United States (<a href="https://archive.epa.gov/epawaste/nonhaz/municipal/web/html/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">28 percent</a>). Several Chinese cities such as <a href="http://www.eco-business.com/news/one-companys-mission-to-turn-chinas-waste-into-energy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Changsha and Zhenjiang</a> have built anaerobic digestion or co-digestion facilities in local sludge treatment plants to produce biogas and fertilizer from waste. However, those plants tend to operate at a loss when feedstock like food scraps is not collected separately at the source. The earlier food waste is separated from other waste streams, the easier it is to use it to produce biogas through anaerobic digestion or <a href="https://www.newsecuritybeat.org/2016/05/innovative-sludge-to-energy-plant-breakthrough-china/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">sludge-to-energy methods</a>.</p><p>The Chinese government has been advocating for sorting waste in cities for almost 20 years, albeit with little progress. In <a href="https://www.chinadialogue.net/article/show/single/en/9812-China-is-sorting-its-household-waste-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2000</a> the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development (MOHURD) designated eight cities (including Beijing, Shanghai, Guangzhou, and Shenzhen) as pilots, forcing the municipalities to implement innovative policies to resolve urban garbage problems. In 2007, MOHURD issued a national regulation to streamline <a href="http://www.mohurd.gov.cn/fgjs/jsbgz/200706/t20070604_159100.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the disposal chain</a> for solid waste, which encouraged individuals and public institutions to separate scraps before dumping them into trash bins. In response, municipal governments have also carried out waste sorting measures in residential areas and public buildings, hoping to resolve the triple threat of shrinking landfill space in urban outskirts, increasing costs of solid waste management, and growing public concerns over waste pollution.</p><h3 id="Why-Is-Sorting-Waste-So-Difficult-in-China"><a href="#Why-Is-Sorting-Waste-So-Difficult-in-China" class="headerlink" title="Why Is Sorting Waste So Difficult in China?"></a>Why Is Sorting Waste So Difficult in China?</h3><p>Though disposal chain regulations have remained in effect for the past 10 years, most Chinese cities still struggle to manage the waste sorting and food waste disposal process. Public awareness and engagement has long been a barrier to classifying and packaging urban waste. Cities along China’s east coast usually have more efficient sorting systems and a higher waste reutilization than their inland counterparts due to strong policies and investment plans for both infrastructure and awareness-building, as well as public oversight by communities and nongovernmental organizations.</p><p>However, in underdeveloped cities, existing noncompulsory regulations have proven less effective at inducing behavioral changes and promoting public participation. In 2014, I surveyed citizens in six cities about their understanding of municipal waste. In Jingzhou—a small river port city of just under one million people located on the banks of the Yangtze River in Hubei Province—eight out of ten interviewees were unaware of the importance of waste classification. “I seldom think of sorting the garbage before dumping it and I don’t think it matters because no one really cares about it,” said one.</p><p>Even after households and restaurants voluntarily separate food waste from recyclables and non-recyclables, there is still a good chance that scraps will mix somewhere else in the process. China’s municipal garbage sorting largely relies on <a href="http://www.coresponsibility.com/report/informal-waste/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">scavengers</a> and workers at sanitation stations. As the market value of food scraps is much lower than recyclables like paper and plastic, both the formal and informal sectors are reluctant to thoroughly sort food waste without financial incentives. In <a href="http://www.sixthtone.com/news/1000294/chinas-latest-trash-sorting-push-not-good-enough%2C-experts-say" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shenzhen</a>, a pilot city for 17 years, 90 percent of local residents are well informed about the waste classification scheme, yet less than 20 percent effectively sort their household waste under the city’s scattered solid waste distribution system.</p><h3 id="Mandatory-Garbage-Sorting-A-New-Hope-for-Food-Waste"><a href="#Mandatory-Garbage-Sorting-A-New-Hope-for-Food-Waste" class="headerlink" title="Mandatory Garbage Sorting: A New Hope for Food Waste?"></a>Mandatory Garbage Sorting: A New Hope for Food Waste?</h3><p>In March 2017, National Development and Reform Commission and MOHURD selected <a href="https://news.cgtn.com/news/3d67544e7a637a4d/share_p.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">46 cities</a> for mandatory garbage sorting, with the goal of achieving a minimal recycling rate of 35 percent by 2020. According to its <a href="http://hzs.ndrc.gov.cn/newzwxx/201703/W020170331321268083586.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">classification standards</a>, the “wet” garbage (food waste) must be separated from the “dry” garbage (other types of waste) in order to reach the recycling threshold. All public institutions, supermarkets, hotels, restaurants, and office buildings are required to follow the rules or face a penalty. Echoing the plan, Chinese municipalities are increasing investments in public education and boosting public-private partnerships for constructing waste infrastructure. For instance, the Beijing city government has built <a href="http://www.shanghaidaily.com/opinion/chinese-perspectives/Beijing-grapples-with-growing-kitchen-waste/shdaily.shtml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">five</a> new waste processing centers and employed more than <a href="http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/cndy/2017-04/13/content_28903270.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">20,000</a> inspectors to improve waste sorting practices. One district government offers to <a href="http://epaper.ynet.com/html/2017-06/05/content_251463.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">pay</a> residents 1700 RMB ($250) for each ton of classified household garbage, in either a monthly lump sum to property managers who then opt to incentivize high-performing households, or a direct award of 0.5 RMB for each disposal.  </p><p>Mandatory waste sorting rules have forced municipal governments in the 46 pilot cities to introduce innovative policies and initiatives to resolve their urban garbage problems. If these rules help change public awareness and habits, introduce clean technology, and use food scraps in sustainable or productive ways, it could pave the way for other cities and villages in China to follow.</p><p><em>Sources: BBC, Beijing Youth Daily, CGTN, China Daily, China Dialogue, China Internet Watch, China.org.cn, Collective Responsibility, Eco-Business, Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development of P. R. China, OECD iLibrary, Shanghai Daily, Six Tones, The New York Times, U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Weibo, Xinhua News Agency.</em></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>blogpost</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>How Shark Attacks (and Other Factors) Affect Your Vote</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/05/10/eu/"/>
    <url>2017/05/10/eu/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a blogpost I wrote for “So what”, the blog of Aspen Planning and Evaluation Program of the Aspen Institute. I wrote about factors that impacts retrospective voting. I incorporated what I have learned from the course Analytical Politics at Harris, which was taught by <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/lrmartineza/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Prof. Luis Martinez</a>.</em></p><p><strong>Please follow this <a href="https://www.aspeninstitute.org/blog-posts/votes-sharks-lottery-tickets-voters-assess-incumbents/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">link</a> for the original post.</strong></p><p>We might think that voters make decisions based on available evidence of politicians’ performance. This is called “retrospective voting.” According to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Morris_P._Fiorina" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Morris P. Fiorina</a>’s book, <a href="http://wikisum.com/w/Fiorina:_Retrospective_Voting_in_American_Elections" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Retrospective Voting in American National Elections</a>, retrospective voters “need only calculate the changes in their own welfare.” Retrospective voting may seem to connect politicians and citizens in a democratic political system: It suggests that voters make rational choices, and that possible changes in their welfare provide a powerful restraint on incumbents’ behaviors.</p><p>But what kind of “evidence” do voters rely on in judging both their welfare — and the responsibility that incumbents have for it? <a href="http://www.princeton.edu/politics/people/display_person.xml?netid=achen" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christopher Achen</a> and <a href="https://my.vanderbilt.edu/larrybartels/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Larry M. Bartels</a> coined the term <a href="http://www.vanderbilt.edu/csdi/research/CSDI_WP_05-2013.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">“blind retrospection,”</a> arguing that voters sometimes rely on pretty irrational measures of “welfare.” Shark attacks, for example. The summer of 1916 saw an outbreak of fatal shark attacks on the Jersey Shore. President Woodrow Wilson suffered the consequences when voters from the three counties affected bit back: after rigorously controlling for other factors, the researchers found that Wilson’s vote in those counties declined around three percent compared to 1912. <a href="https://www.povertyactionlab.org/bagues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Manuel Bagues</a> and <a href="http://people.laps.yorku.ca/people.nsf/researcherprofile?readform&shortname=bertaev" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Berta Esteve-Volart</a> also demonstrate in <a href="http://www.manuelbagues.com/bagues%20&%20esteve-volart%20-%20economic%20voting.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this study of Spanish electorates</a> that votes for incumbents in a given province increase significantly when residents of that province win “El Gordo” – the annual Christmas Lottery.</p><p>So are voters dumb? Relax — here is some good news. Voters respond well to information such as <a href="https://eml.berkeley.edu/~ffinan/Finan_Audit.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">exposure of corruption</a>, <a href="http://egcenter.economics.yale.edu/sites/default/files/files/Guiteras2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">news reports on politicians</a>, and <a href="https://economics.mit.edu/files/3122" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the performance of former politicians</a> who share similar characteristics with the candidates. Besides, sometimes seemingly random voting decisions are not so random. After all, perhaps the federal government could have done something to protect those hapless swimmers – or done more after the attacks to support the tourist economy “down the Shore.”</p><p>So enjoy your beach weeks, keep an eye out for sharks, and don’t blame the county comptroller if it rains.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>blogpost</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Norse Mythology</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/02/15/norse/"/>
    <url>2017/02/15/norse/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of <strong><em>Norse Mythology</em></strong> by <strong>Neil Gaiman</strong>.</p><p>还是GAIMAN的书。薄薄的一本，和美国众神风格迥异，但说实话我更喜欢这本书。</p><p>Odin为了获得无与伦比的智慧付出了一只眼睛；Hel是Loki和女巨人的女儿；Thor的锤子Mjollnir是矮人工匠打造的，但是由于Loki从中作梗，锤柄短了一截。还有智慧的Kvasir、能够返老还童的Idunn、除了Loki没人不喜欢的Balder……整本书基本上就是一个北欧神话科普，但我还不确定这些故事是GAIMAN瞎编的还是真实口耳相传下来的。</p><p>很有趣的是，在GAIMAN的想象里，没有十全十美的神祗，他们和凡人一样狡诈、自私、贪生怕死。最后关于诸神黄昏的描写特别酷，Loki和他的三个私生子组成军队向诸神宣战，最终的结局是大家同归于尽，连太阳都陨落了。但最终的最终，一切又得以重新开始，Balder和Hod重生，带着侥幸活下来的孩子们下棋。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>book review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>American Gods</title>
    <link href="undefined2017/01/28/american-gods/"/>
    <url>2017/01/28/american-gods/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of <strong><em>American Gods</em></strong> by <strong>Neil Gaiman</strong>.</p><p>这是一个关于混乱和矛盾的故事，古老的神正渐渐被世界淡忘，而新的神：城市、高速公路、媒体和电子游戏正当其道。奥丁找到了自己遗落在凡间的儿子shadow，让他帮助自己笼络旧神，与“世界先生”带领的新神开战。可影子到最后才发现，这一切竟然只是以死亡为食的奥丁的阴谋，和他合谋的就是伪装成世界先生、以混乱为食的洛基。</p><p>GAIMAN在后记里写，他一直担心有人会质疑他作为一个英国人，怎么敢狂妄地试图描绘出一个关于美国的土生土长的故事。但我觉得他做得挺好的，美国本身就是一个新旧、内外混杂矛盾的国家，是殖民者最成功的作品，这种特点贯穿了整个故事：神明不再高高在上，反而有着许多普通人也有的脆弱和烦恼。没有什么是永恒的，除了变化本身；没有什么是完美的，最完美的东西往往最无用；也没有什么是不死的，人人皆可死，神亦可死，但这片土地和它孕育的生命永远存在、永无止息。</p><p>看完这本书才知道原来已经有人拿它当剧本拍出东西来了，可看了一个预告我就失望了。这本书远不止要讲一个奇幻炫目的故事，它还想表达一种理解，一种旁观者对一类文明、一个国家的理解。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>book review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>