<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>HPRP and Household Consumption</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/09/22/HPRP/"/>
    <url>2019/09/22/HPRP/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="1-Introduction"><a href="#1-Introduction" class="headerlink" title="1 Introduction"></a>1 Introduction</h3><p>The mid 1990s witnessed a drastic and long-lasting boom in China’s real estate sector.  The hike in housing prices was primarily realized through the following two channels: first, incentivized by enormous fiscal revenue from selling lands to real estate developers, local governments forcefully introduced a series of policies that accelerate the development of housing markets; second, after abandoning the welfare housing system, city residents’ demands on housing hikes. Plus, with the advancements in marketization, the wealth effect of lands and housing also makes them considerably appealing to investors. As a result, housing prices have been skyrocketing: real growth in house prices averages 10% per annum since 2006 (Gyourko et al, 2016).</p><p>While the real estate sector remains a key component of the Chinese economy, the soaring housing prices engender concerns related to the stability of China’s financial system and macro fundamentals, as well as to the welfare of individual household. The authorities have certainly recognized these issues. Since 2005, a series of policies were enacted to regulate the housing market. First introduced in 2010, Housing Purchase Restriction Policy (HPRP) remains one of the most powerful policy tools to curb the soaring housing prices. According to the “NO. 10 National Notice” (2010) issued by the State Council, non-residents (people without registered permanent residency, or “Hukou” ) who paid taxes or social security for less than a year to the city they reside would not be eligible for mortgage loans. It also granted municipalities the authority to control the number of houses or apartments residents and nonresidents can buy. Temporarily relaxed in 2014, HPRP now remains in action in 60 cities.</p><p>There have been plenty of measures and studies on the regulation the housing markets, but most of them target at the supply side. Gyourko and Molloy (2015) has done an impressive work reviewing research on housing supply regulations (outside China), and concluded that based on available evidence, most studies found negative net welfare effects from regulations. Measures that restrict housing demands, however, are rare. In this sense, HPRP is valuable as it serves as a unique social experiment complementing the studies on market regulations. Just like other types of government interventions, HPRP has great implications on social welfare. There exists abundant literature on HPRP and its effects. Most, if not all, focus on its interactions with housing markets. A bulk of research examine the interdependency between HPRP and housing prices (Zhang, 2016). Some research focuses on how HPRP influences housing markets and how these impacts may differ (Du, 2015; Fang, 2018; Cao and Huang, 2015; Cao, 2017; Lu, 2018; Tzur-Ilan, 2016; Fang, 2018; Chen, 2018; Wu, 2016; Wu and Li, 2017). There do exist some attempts evaluating the welfare effects of HPRP, but mostly by building theoretical frameworks (Li, 2011; Hu 2011; Feng and He, 2012). In addition, it is also useful to evaluate the variations in welfare consequences across different groups (Gyourko, 2015). Thus, I am interested in how HPRP reshape the welfare of individual households, especially how the effects might differ across families with distinct characteristics.</p><p>In this study, I intend to measure the net effects of HPRP on household consumption which is a commonly used proxy for welfare (Garner et al, 2003). HPRP is meant to increase the affordability of housings by stifling speculative demands. When housing purchases are restricted, money that is originally spent on housing will then be diverted into either the consumption of other goods or reinvestments on other assets (Mao, 2011). On the other hand, housing also serves as a capital good whose value grows with price. As evaluated by Wu et al (2012), the expected capital gain from housing is quite high in China. As a result, under HPRP, families can no longer invest in the housing market and thus lose one avenue for investing. Decreases in future returns might discourage household consumption. In addition, whether families regard housings as necessities or means of investments should be primarily determined by household characteristics such as financial conditions and preferences. Thus, depending on individual characteristics, influences of HPRP on households vary. There exist several channels via which HPRP introduced differential impacts (Feng and He, 2012). Families owning one or more houses can be driven away from housing to other consumption markets by HPRP. Alternatively, families that have not owned housings and are not eligible for purchase might increase savings. As these forces are in opposite directions, I am curious about the net effects of HPRP on households’ consumption and how these effects vary across groups. Whilst research on the dynamics of housings prices and consumption is plentiful, few are conducted in the context of HPRP (Dong et al, 2017). Moreover, existing researches at best touched on the effects of HPRP from a macro perspective (Zhang, 2016; Du et al, 2015; Lu, 2018). Few analyzes HPRP from a micro level (Mo, 2015). Although there have already been some works on the correlations between HPRP and consumption, they either focus solely on housing markets or use macro-level data (Mo, 2015; Feng and He, 2012). With access to micro-level data on household finance and demographic features, this paper will try to find empirical evidence on how HPRP influences the welfare of individual family.</p><p>Given the dramatic variations in specific terms of HPRP adopted by municipalities, our study focuses on one specific regulation used by nearly all cities – the number of houses a family can purchase given their “Hukou” and housing ownership status, and control for other bundled policies. I also care most about how HPRP influences households’ consumption on goods other than housing, particularly on education and entertainment. Inverse demand system will be used given the fact that HPRP is constraining the quantity of demand, which makes it more appropriate to take quantity as exogenous when analyzing the markets. To compare how the effects of HPRP might differ regarding individual attributes, I will first identify households living in cities that have enforced HPRP, then utilize Propensity Score Matching (PSM) to construct a control group from households (in other regions) not subject to HPRP but with similar characteristics. Several features characterize HPRP as a quasi-experiment: first, cities have some latitude in determining whether to adopt HPRP or not; second, some cities implemented HPRP while others did not; third, eligibility under HPRP can be argued to be exogenous – “Hukou” and number of houses owned were generally determined prior to the HPRP. In order to measure and compare how the results might differ across different types of households, I divide households into three groups based on the attributes of their demands. We are then able to measure the causal relations between HPRP and the consumption of different types of households via a Difference-in-Difference approach (DiD).</p><h3 id="2-Theoretical-framework-and-hypothesis"><a href="#2-Theoretical-framework-and-hypothesis" class="headerlink" title="2 Theoretical framework and hypothesis"></a>2 Theoretical framework and hypothesis</h3><h4 id="2-1-The-loss-of-welfare-induced-by-HPRP"><a href="#2-1-The-loss-of-welfare-induced-by-HPRP" class="headerlink" title="2.1 The loss of welfare induced by HPRP"></a>2.1 The loss of welfare induced by HPRP</h4><p>In light of the studies on Harberger Triangle of welfare and the supply and demand model (Glaeser 2003; Hu, 2011; Feng and He, 2012; Canning and Vroomen, 2019), HPRP and its interaction with the housing market can be presented as Graph 1.</p><p>HPRP restricts housing purchase by a set of regulatory criteria, including “Hukou”, the number of housings owned by households and the amount of down payment. This design is equivalent to dividing up consumer population into groups based on their eligibility. New demands in housing markets are subsamples from each group (Hu, 2011). Thus, the demand curve would shift inward under HPRP (D’ in Graph 1). Notice that for individual households in the same group, their eligibility of housing purchase is the same. I then assume that the “sampling process” within each group is somewhat random. Further notice that I cannot determine the allocation among different groups and its correlations with group characteristics without empirical evidence. That is, I do not make any specific assumptions about the intercept and the slope of D’. In Graph 1, I let D’ have a smaller elasticity compared to D, but it can be just the opposite in reality.</p><p>Technically, HPRP is very likely to induce welfare loss. The welfare loss generated by HPRP is then determined by the slope and intercept of this new curve (Graph 1). Note that D’ represents the new demand curve under HPRP. The deadweight loss (DWL) from HPRP is the polygon BOCF. This DWL is assumed to be greater than a quantity control scenario (denoted by the vertical line AC) by the area of BACF.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>research</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Courage to Act</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/02/28/courage/"/>
    <url>2019/02/28/courage/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This a short review of the book <em>The Courage to Act: A Memoir of A Crisis and Its Aftermath</em> by Ben Bernanke.</p><ol><li><p>This book solves a lot of puzzles on central banking for me. The first one coming into my mind should be the “boundary issue”. On the one hand, central banks should maintain its nonpartisan stance so that it can “moves” the market objectively. On the other hand, it is also the responsibility of central bankers to coordinate the economic policies and make sure everything is in alignment of the policy targets. In addition, should we expect the central banks to foresee systematic risks and acts as a safety net when crises hit the economy?</p></li><li><p>It seems that the priority of monetary policy making is to consider what the change in policy could do to the market expectation. Quote Mr. Bernanke, 98% of the effectiveness of monetary policy depends on communication with the market. However, examples offered in the book (such as the implementation of quantitative easing and the rescue of )</p></li><li><p>I was always wondering if it is rational to use “cycle” to explain the booms and busts of literally every macroeconomic phenomenon, and use this line of logic to forecast the future. Does history really repeat itself? Mr. Bernanke did mention this question in his book, though he simply quoted Mark Twain that “history may rhyme, but does not repeat itself”. So now the question becomes: to what extent would history rhyme?</p></li><li><p>The fuses of crises often seem to be bank runs (though in different forms). So what is the root of crises? What makes the market panic at the very beginning? Is there a factor that can conclude these panics?</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>short review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Norse Mythology</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/02/15/norse/"/>
    <url>2019/02/15/norse/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><pre><code class="bash">$ hexo new &quot;My New Post&quot;</code></pre><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><pre><code class="bash">$ hexo server</code></pre><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><pre><code class="bash">$ hexo generate</code></pre><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><pre><code class="bash">$ hexo deploy</code></pre><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/deployment.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>short review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Trumponomics</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/01/29/trumponomics/"/>
    <url>2019/01/29/trumponomics/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol><li><p>This book solves a lot of puzzles on central banking for me. The first one coming into my mind should be the “boundary issue”. On the one hand, central banks should maintain its nonpartisan stance so that it can “moves” the market objectively. On the other hand, it is also the responsibility of central bankers to coordinate the economic policies and make sure everything is in alignment of the policy targets. In addition, should we expect the central banks to foresee systematic risks and acts as a safety net when crises hit the economy?</p></li><li><p>It seems that the priority of monetary policy making is to consider what the change in policy could do to the market expectation. Quote Mr. Bernanke, 98% of the effectiveness of monetary policy depends on communication with the market. However, examples offered in the book (such as the implementation of quantitative easing and the rescue of )</p></li><li><p>I was always wondering if it is rational to use “cycle” to explain the booms and busts of literally every macroeconomic phenomenon, and use this line of logic to forecast the future. Does history really repeat itself? Mr. Bernanke did mention this question in his book, though he simply quoted Mark Twain that “history may rhyme, but does not repeat itself”. So now the question becomes: to what extent would history rhyme?</p></li><li><p>The fuses of crises often seem to be bank runs (though in different forms). So what is the root of crises? What makes the market panic at the very beginning? Is there a factor that can conclude these panics?</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>short review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>American Gods</title>
    <link href="undefined2019/01/28/american-gods/"/>
    <url>2019/01/28/american-gods/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol><li><p>This book solves a lot of puzzles on central banking for me. The first one coming into my mind should be the “boundary issue”. On the one hand, central banks should maintain its nonpartisan stance so that it can “moves” the market objectively. On the other hand, it is also the responsibility of central bankers to coordinate the economic policies and make sure everything is in alignment of the policy targets. In addition, should we expect the central banks to foresee systematic risks and acts as a safety net when crises hit the economy?</p></li><li><p>It seems that the priority of monetary policy making is to consider what the change in policy could do to the market expectation. Quote Mr. Bernanke, 98% of the effectiveness of monetary policy depends on communication with the market. However, examples offered in the book (such as the implementation of quantitative easing and the rescue of )</p></li><li><p>I was always wondering if it is rational to use “cycle” to explain the booms and busts of literally every macroeconomic phenomenon, and use this line of logic to forecast the future. Does history really repeat itself? Mr. Bernanke did mention this question in his book, though he simply quoted Mark Twain that “history may rhyme, but does not repeat itself”. So now the question becomes: to what extent would history rhyme?</p></li><li><p>The fuses of crises often seem to be bank runs (though in different forms). So what is the root of crises? What makes the market panic at the very beginning? Is there a factor that can conclude these panics?</p></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>short review</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>